<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-25T18:42:29-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">The Brooklyn Latineer</title><subtitle>The online home of the Brooklyn Latineer</subtitle><author><name>The Latineer</name><email>tblsnewspaper@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Don’t Appropriate, Appreciate.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/opinion/OpinionsWhatisCulturalAppropriation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don't Appropriate, Appreciate." /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/opinion/OpinionsWhatisCulturalAppropriation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/opinion/OpinionsWhatisCulturalAppropriation/">&lt;p&gt;On November 20th, 2016, a &lt;em&gt;Blackhair&lt;/em&gt; beauty magazine stirred up quite the controversy when the cover page featured Emily Bador, a white model, providing tips on how to maintain curly and frizzy hair. The problem there was that Emily Bador is a white woman attempting to convey the true beauty of an element of African-American culture. This issue led to an outpour of displeasure, which died down after she took her Instagram as a platform to apologize for the blatant cultural appropriation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the world didn’t stop appropriating: &lt;em&gt;Fuller House&lt;/em&gt; committed an equally serious blunder with another culture. News that Netflix would refresh the TV family sitcom “&lt;em&gt;Full House”&lt;/em&gt; with the same cast was cause for rejoice for many. When Season One finally aired in February 2016, all seemed well. Then came the eleventh episode, in which an Indian-themed party was thrown by a character named Kimmy Gibbler. You may be wondering what exactly the issue may be in this instance. To begin, there was not anyone of Indian descent even present at the party. It was just white males and females dressed in traditional Indian clothings such as “sherwanis” and “saris.” Furthermore, the show had the temerity to jokingly place a cow in the party and dress it up solely for use as a comedic prop. I [Deep] witnessed this example of cultural appropriation firsthand as I watched the episode and, to say the least, I was simply baffled. Thousands of years of heritage and tradition were diminished to a party unrepresentative of Indian culture as a whole and solely present for the enjoyment of individuals who have held more privilege in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anecdotes like this are just one of hundreds that grace the covers of newspapers every year. But the sad, blunt truth is that we haven’t. In its simplest form, cultural appropriation is when one group adopts elements from another culture without either acknowledging its cultural significance, or even going as far as claiming it as their own–hence, mocking it to an extent. A common counter used by many perpetrators of cultural appropriation is that they are simply participating in cultural exchange: a trading of elements of a different culture for the sake of emphasizing each one’s value. That, as seen from the anecdotes above, is nowhere near what we so often wrongly do. We must understand that it is not wrong to borrow elements from another culture. However, we must be willing to learn and understand what exactly we are “borrowing” from their culture. We must note the cultural relevance and have an open-mind in experiencing all aspects of it. It is imperative to let individuals of those cultures show how th&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Sophie Wang&quot;, &quot;Deep Patel&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">On November 20th, 2016, a Blackhair beauty magazine stirred up quite the controversy when the cover page featured Emily Bador, a white model, providing tips on how to maintain curly and frizzy hair. The problem there was that Emily Bador is a white woman attempting to convey the true beauty of an element of African-American culture. This issue led to an outpour of displeasure, which died down after she took her Instagram as a platform to apologize for the blatant cultural appropriation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Talk Less Smile More</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/opinion/OpinionsTalkLessSmileMore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talk Less Smile More" /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/opinion/OpinionsTalkLessSmileMore</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/opinion/OpinionsTalkLessSmileMore/">&lt;p&gt;The question is simple: should we simplify our word choice when talking in seminar? Here are our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ralph:&lt;/strong&gt; We shouldn’t sacrifice our freedom of diction just to appeal to larger audience. We should be able to use the words that we want to express our ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexis:&lt;/strong&gt; I think that the use of academic jargon can be harmful when speaking in seminar because your message becomes lost in your frills of your vocabulary. It’s exclusionary. Is it not in your best interest to project your ideas so that the group as a whole can understand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R:&lt;/strong&gt; Elevated language isn’t meant to harm the core message. Of course, there are people out there using a word just because it’s long or sounds nice so that they sound clever. They aren’t always thinking about their intended message. We shouldn’t discredit the power of language just because a few people aren’t using it right. A real world example? You can’t say people should use always screwdrivers instead of wrenches. The blame falls on the mechanic for using the wrong tools for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; It isn’t realistic to expect someone to completely vanquish sophistication from their speech. I argue that moderation is the answer. When using complex language, small misunderstandings can compound, ultimately degrading understanding of your overarching point. Doesn’t that detract from your purpose as an orator?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R:&lt;/strong&gt; There will always be people that don’t understand your language. Why not make your point more approachable for those who do understand you by using words that perfectly fit your thoughts? I agree with you when you argue for moderation, but I don’t think anyone should be limited in what words they use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Seminar is meant to broaden understanding of a topic through educated discussion. If people don’t understand, that’s an issue: understanding is crucial to a productive seminar. While academic jargon can often be more condensed, that doesn’t always result in clarity. For example, “infinitesimal” versus “really really small.” Both accurately portray the same idea. Which do you think is more specific?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R:&lt;/strong&gt; Since familiarity with the phrase is assumed, we can focus on our core argument. A good speaker defines new terms. If not, it never hurts to ask them. We’re building out collective vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; It is impractical for students in seminar to Google a word or Latin phrase they’ve never heard. I’d rather a peer reflect on revelations of an idea I present rather than the meaning of some obscure word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, yeah I see what you’re saying. At the same time though, I can’t help but appreciate the fact that your language is really sophisticated and elegant, and I think it really gives your argument a real “wow” factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; I like that your speech is really simple and to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R:&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe we both need a bit of our own advice.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Ralph Vente&quot;, &quot;Alexis  David&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">The question is simple: should we simplify our word choice when talking in seminar? Here are our thoughts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Istanbul Nightclub Shooting Scars Turkey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/NewsTurkey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Istanbul Nightclub Shooting Scars Turkey" /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/NewsTurkey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/NewsTurkey/">&lt;p&gt;This past New Year’s Eve, there was a shooting at a nightclub in Istanbul, Turkey. 69 people were wounded and 39 were killed. Of the 69 wounded, several were left in critical condition. Only twenty-one dead were identified. Of the 21 dead, 16 were determined to be of foreign nationality, with the remaining five being Turkish. Both Turkey and the United States have called it a terrorist attack. After the shooting, twelve suspects were taken into custody, and apprehending the shooter became a top priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 17th, Governor Vasip Sahin of Istanbul announced that a suspect named Abdulgadir Masharipov confessed to committing the New Year’s shooting. Masharipov is from Uzbekistan and spent his educational years in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact events of the attack are unclear to police at this time. Police do know that the attacker shot a police officer who was guarding the entrance, and then went in to shoot civilians. Some witness accounts suggest the presence of multiple attackers. The bar at which the attack took place was in a highly populated area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to the New Year’s Eve shooting, Turkey had been subject to multiple attacks, which caused several Turkish citizens to stay home on New Year’s Eve. ISIS has claimed responsibility for several of these attacks, stating them to be acts of revenge against Turkey for the country’s attempts to push back the Islamic State’s forces in Syria. There are reportedly increasing tensions between the extremist group and Turkey for killing Muslims via air strikes and mortar attacks. In August of 2016, Turkish forces started a campaign against the Jihadist movement and since then have lead several airstrikes. While combatting this, Turkey has played a large role in helping negotiate peace treaties between the Syrian government and groups of moderate rebels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBLS discipuli had, overall, negative responses to the tragedy. Many discipuli are astonished  by the recent slew of tragedies. “I just think in general too many awful things are happening in the world. I think too many things are happening too fast for me to have an opinion on them,” said Eva Schenk, Class III, when asked about the events in Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others felt that ISIS was being particularly hypocritical. Noor Al-Muzahid, Class IV, felt that the Islamic State’s reasoning for the attack–that Turkish soldiers had killed Muslims in Syria–was hypocritical, saying, “I don’t believe it was done in the name of Islam. Why would ISIS attack a notable Islamic country and kill innocent Muslims?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding America’s involvement, Class IV discipulus Quentin Livingston felt that “We [America] as a nation need to be harder on terrorism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quentin was not the only discipulus who felt that America was not contributing enough. One Class IV discipula, Sierra Parris, responded to Trump’s recent actions and said, “This is what Trump needs to be focused on, not banning immigrants from seven countries that have no history of terrorism.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Desmond Keuper</name></author><summary type="html">This past New Year’s Eve, there was a shooting at a nightclub in Istanbul, Turkey. 69 people were wounded and 39 were killed. Of the 69 wounded, several were left in critical condition. Only twenty-one dead were identified. Of the 21 dead, 16 were determined to be of foreign nationality, with the remaining five being Turkish. Both Turkey and the United States have called it a terrorist attack. After the shooting, twelve suspects were taken into custody, and apprehending the shooter became a top priority.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trump’s Innaguration: A New Era.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/NewsTrumpsInauguration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trump's Innaguration: A New Era." /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/NewsTrumpsInauguration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/NewsTrumpsInauguration/">&lt;p&gt;On January 20th 2016, the nation entered a new era: Donald Trump was sworn in as the 45th President of the United States of America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Chief Justice Roberts, President Carter, President Clinton, President Bush, President Obama, fellow Americans and people of the world,” President Trump said at the start of his Inaugural Address.”Thank you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ceremony was held in front of the Capitol with an estimated 160,000 people attending. The theme of the inauguration mirrored his slogan throughout his campaign for office–Make America Great Again.  President Trump’s inauguration marked the first president without any experience in either military or government. He is also the oldest and wealthiest president ever to be sworn in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his Inaugural Address, President Trump stressed the flaws of the past establishment of government and that that he will be the one to revise those flaws. He discussed the hardships he has seen America endure, stating, “Mothers and children trapped in poverty in our inner cities; rusted-out factories scattered like tombstones across the landscape of our nation; an education system flush with cash, but which leaves our young and beautiful students deprived of knowledge; and the crime and gangs and drugs that have stolen too many lives and robbed our country of so much unrealized potential.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following these descriptions of America’s shortcoming, he again promised that he will be the one who fix them. “I will fight for you with every breath in my body and I will never, ever let you down,” President Trump assured American citizens..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to know what the future might hold, but one resounding sentiment seems likely to impact futures across the globe: for President Trump, “From this day forward, it’s going to be only America first, America first.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chloe Li</name></author><summary type="html">On January 20th 2016, the nation entered a new era: Donald Trump was sworn in as the 45th President of the United States of America.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No Longer on the Queue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/NewsNoLongerontheQueue/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Longer on the Queue" /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/NewsNoLongerontheQueue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/NewsNoLongerontheQueue/">&lt;p&gt;No Longer on the Queue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gracie Zheng&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with 2017 came the opening of the first phase of the Second Avenue Subway, a project first proposed in 1929 that took almost a century to get going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The construction of the Second Avenue line has been split into 4 phases, the first of which is already complete. Phase One was the extension of the Q train from Lexington Avenue/ 63rd St to three subway stations created along the Upper East Side at 72nd, 86th, and 96th Streets. In the second phase, the Q train will grow even further, adding three more stations to reach 125th Street, where it will link to the 4/5/6 train. In the third and fourth phases, ten new stations will be created, ranging from where the Q train originates at 72 St all the way to Hanover Square in the Lower East Side. This new line will be covered by the T train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the TBLS community’s response to these developments has been positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s helpful to me because it is much less crowded than the 4/5/6 line in the morning. I get to leave a little bit later in order to get to TBLS,” says History Magistra Lauren Filipink. “[The transfer] to the L train is also much easier.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class III discipulus Chengang Zhang relays a similar message. To him, “[The new line is] most definitely a benefit to my journey, as it cuts down my commute to school which allows me to squeeze in a little more sleep time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, the Second Avenue subway has brought access to the Upper East Side. New York looks forward to an extension downwards to the Lower East Side in the next couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gracie Zheng</name></author><summary type="html">No Longer on the Queue</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Ocatvi Conondrum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/features/FeaturesOcatviConundrum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ocatvi Conondrum" /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/features/FeaturesOcatviConundrum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/features/FeaturesOcatviConundrum/">&lt;p&gt;February 7, 2017 bore witness to a confluence of events the likes of which Brooklyn Latin has never seen. It was the day scores of discipuli rose up and walked out of class to protest the confirmation of Secretary of Education Betsy Devos in Manhattan’s Foley Square. It was the day a Junior/Senior approbation ceremony was uncharacteristically unattended. And it was the day Class I discipuli were overcome by anguish over their Senior tees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the approbation ceremony, Juniors darted home while the Seniors who had elected not to attend the walk-out swarmed the auditorium stage. Massive CustomInk boxes were strategically positioned along the stage’s edge. Eager hands inched towards the boxes, only to be shooed away by the authoritative gaze of Magister Matthew Baker as he did his best to orchestrate the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, magistri divided into hand-out squadrons based on students’ last names. Eagerly the crowd rearranged itself into a somewhat more orderly state. Then from above rained purple tees as magistri belted out names and hurled shirts in the general direction of the owner. Early receivers shuffled out, grinning and admiring the tee’s classy font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ELECTISSIMI OCTAVI (“Elite Eight”) read the shirt—or so they thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, all came to the same, haunting realization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emblazoned across the front was a glorious “ELECTISSIMI OCATVI.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our four years of Latin had been for nothing!” some said; “Magistra Storniolo! Have you seen this?” asked others incredulously; “Aw shucks,” remarked the situationally detached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then of course there was the quintessential “I want my money back!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was an honest mistake. An unfortunate, expensive mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is one which has since been rectified with a round of replacement shirts, which miraculously made it to school just in time for Senior T-Shirt day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The takeaway: chuckle heartily and remember that for Class I time now runs short, too short.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jack Ryan Sarmiento</name><email>tblslatineer@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">February 7, 2017 bore witness to a confluence of events the likes of which Brooklyn Latin has never seen. It was the day scores of discipuli rose up and walked out of class to protest the confirmation of Secretary of Education Betsy Devos in Manhattan’s Foley Square. It was the day a Junior/Senior approbation ceremony was uncharacteristically unattended. And it was the day Class I discipuli were overcome by anguish over their Senior tees.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Media Lacks Proper LGBTQIA Representation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/features/FeaturesLGBTQIARepresentation3091characters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Media Lacks Proper LGBTQIA Representation" /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/features/FeaturesLGBTQIARepresentation3091characters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/features/FeaturesLGBTQIARepresentation3091characters/">&lt;p&gt;If you are a cis—or straight—white male, there is no shortage of representation for you in movies, books, and TV shows. Each celebrates you as a well-rounded character. Cis men can have different personalities: they can be nerdy, strong, confident. However, if you’re a LGBTQIA person, this is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who are not straight or cisgender suffer from a lack of representation in media. The representation we do get is reduced to stereotypes: the white gay man as the ‘flamboyant best friend’  or the occasional ‘butch’ lesbian. These characters often remain the supportive, single character who lack interests of their own and has no desire for romance. If not this, the gay man is reduced to a lustful, hypersexualized person who preys on men regardless of whether they seem to reciprocate these feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard for bisexual, pansexual, asexual, and aromantic individuals to find any representation whatsoever, let alone accurate representation. In media, individuals who are shown to be attracted to two or more genders are often not labeled as bisexual or pansexual; instead, these characters explain themselves as ‘swinging both ways’ or not wanting to ‘label myself.’ While the LGBTQIA community understands and respects that labels are not for everyone, this statement is likely used to refrain from the actual use of the words ‘bisexual’ or ‘pansexual,’ so as to not lose their homophobic viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, asexual and aromantic individuals are never recognized in the media—if they are, they are ridiculed and patronized. Overabundant in entertainment are romantic and sexual subplots involving romantic and sexual acts. Even children are given love interests. And that’s only sexual and romantic orientation: the gender spectrum is also poorly represented in media. Representation of transgender individuals is either harmful, misleading, or limited. Worse yet, individuals who do not conform to the gender binary and are not out as trans are suspected as gay, and often ridiculed in media. Even if a character has shown no interest in romance or sexual attraction, the default for every individual presented on a screen is straight and cisgender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representation matters. As Mo Barbier, Class I, stated, “when you identify with a character in a form that you never thought you would identify ever, it awakens something in you.” It is important to recognize the effect that representation—be it positive or negative—has on us. Movies, TV shows, and books are all important aspects of pop culture, and hold more influence than you think; people often reference them as an impactful means to learn and grow. That is what good, accurate representation can do for the confused, frightened, and ostracised members of the LGBTQIA community: it can help them learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cat Meza U.</name><email>ketevani.meza@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">If you are a cis—or straight—white male, there is no shortage of representation for you in movies, books, and TV shows. Each celebrates you as a well-rounded character. Cis men can have different personalities: they can be nerdy, strong, confident. However, if you’re a LGBTQIA person, this is not the case.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vale, Obama!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/features/news/entertainment/sports/opinion/FeaturesKenjaminLatineerthingy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vale, Obama!" /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/features/news/entertainment/sports/opinion/FeaturesKenjaminLatineerthingy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/features/news/entertainment/sports/opinion/FeaturesKenjaminLatineerthingy/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;coauthored-by-benjamin-leung-kenny-chen&quot;&gt;Coauthored by Benjamin Leung, Kenny Chen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As President Trump starts a new era with his presidency, the Latineer would like to  reflect on the eight years Barack Obama held the presidential office and administered the country. Of course, like those before him, President Barack Obama was by no means “perfect president.” Yet from the moment he took the oath of office on January 20, 2009, Obama led America through some of its most difficult and tumultuous times. It is now that we, as Americans, must remember some of the most significant events that occurred during Obama’s presidency. Here are 5 most memorable moments during his presidency that are undeniably worth celebrating and looking back on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visit to Cuba&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March of 2016, Obama made a visit to Cuba, being the first president to set foot in that country in nearly 9 decades. Due to their differences in government and difficult relationship, a barrier was formed between Cuba and The United States.  However, this visit started to break down this barrier and improved foreign relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Creation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Great Recession, which began in 2007, 8.7 million jobs were lost. With the sudden decline in jobs, the unemployment rate peaked at 10%.  However, Obama steadily erased the job deficit by creating 15 million jobs starting in 2010, the most by any president excluding Ronald Reagan and Bill Clinton.  This put many Americans back to work and improved the economy tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issuing Obamacare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Obama’s presidency, healthcare was becoming too costly for Medicare to cover.  As a result, many people were in danger of losing coverage provided by health insurance.  On March 23, 2010, in an effort to reform healthcare, Obama introduced his policy of Obamacare, which gave 95% of the population affordable health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet Exploded with Memes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the days leading up to Obama’s resignation, the internet exploded with memes of President Obama and Vice President Joe Biden’s “bromance.” When referring to their friendship, many described the two as “the two best friends we wished we had” or as the Washington Post put it: a “bond strongest in White House history.” Of course, the President’s notable charm and charisma fueled the fire as he stated, &lt;em&gt;‘I love that man. He’s not just a great vice president, he is a great friend. We’ve gotten so close in some places in Indiana, they won’t serve us pizza anymore.’&lt;/em&gt; Mr. President, your wit and humour is surely to be missed, but your memes will forever be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marriage Equality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During his presidency,Obama called for a Supreme Court ruling that required states to recognize gay marriage. Time and time again, he referred to it as a “victory for America.” He was even the first president to mention the word “transgender” in a State of the Union address. His rallying cry for equality contributed to significant changes in the LGBTQ+ community as it not only legitimized their relationships, but also reemphasizing their rights as an American. WIth his support, the Supreme Court Justice finally made same-sex marriage legal nationwide on June 26, 2015, affecting millions of Americans nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so many memories, accomplishments, and notable qualities, President Obama and his family will surely be remembered and celebrated for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>[&quot;Benjamin Leung&quot;, &quot;Kenny Chen&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html">Coauthored by Benjamin Leung, Kenny Chen</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The New 1984: Emergence of Fake News</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/features/Features1984/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The New 1984: Emergence of Fake News" /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/features/Features1984</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/features/Features1984/">&lt;p&gt;With the recent mention of fake news in the media, an Orwellian quote came to mind: “Political language is designed to make lies sound truthful and murder respectable, and to give an appearance of solidity to pure wind.” Wind is nothing. Fake news is turning nothing into something. Now, actual facts have become rarer to find and the new “truth” often manipulates people to think blindly about recent events. Fake news alters various ideologies to gain passionate support. This is present at a dystopian society such as in “1984” by George Orwell, and it is becoming more of a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a search for scholarly insight, the Latineer turned to History Magistra Lauren Filipink. She defined the term as, “Fake news is manufactured stories that contain real and recognized individuals and plausible situations intended to manipulate or reinforce the perspective of the writer or reader.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fake news is difficult to distinguish, she noted. “I like to think it hasn’t affected me because I can identify fake news,” she added. “ I try to be selective about what I read and who I follow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthering her thought she mentioned the resultance of fake news, “I don’t think it threatens our democracy if we truly believe in personal liberty and freedom of the press.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presence of fake news bears challenge to history Magistras such as Ms. Filipink herself. She noted, “I do feel as though a burden falls on me as a History teacher. A lot of our instruction is based on reading history and understanding the values and limitations of what we read or view. Maybe now that’s going to transform into teaching how to detect what’s real and what’s fake. I do worry that people are using the term ‘fake news’ to label sources that their personal views aren’t necessarily aligned with.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is, fake news should be considered a concern due how it skews the perspective of the reader, leading one to believe falsehoods, and causing them to take actions such as rioting or even war. Keeping the truth alive can start here, in TBLS - and being alert when it pertains to the media can help discipuli not believe in the “solidity [of] pure wind” .&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noor Muzahid</name></author><summary type="html">With the recent mention of fake news in the media, an Orwellian quote came to mind: “Political language is designed to make lies sound truthful and murder respectable, and to give an appearance of solidity to pure wind.” Wind is nothing. Fake news is turning nothing into something. Now, actual facts have become rarer to find and the new “truth” often manipulates people to think blindly about recent events. Fake news alters various ideologies to gain passionate support. This is present at a dystopian society such as in “1984” by George Orwell, and it is becoming more of a reality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Rogue to Look Out For</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/entertainment/BackpageRogueOne/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Rogue to Look Out For" /><published>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/entertainment/BackpageRogueOne</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/entertainment/BackpageRogueOne/">&lt;p&gt;“I am one with the force—the force is with me” rings the mantra of warrior-monk Chirrut Îmwe in the latest film in the Star Wars universe: “Rogue One.” The force was indeed with “Rogue One” as it earned more than 800 million dollars its opening weekend. Chronologically, “Rogue” One” falls between Episodes 3 and 4, filling in the events leading up to the destruction of the first Death Star. The plot centers around Jyn Erso, the daughter of a scientist forced by the Empire to help build a planet-destroying weapon: the Death Star. As a child, Imperial Deathtroopers stormed Jyn’s planet, killing her mother, and kidnapping her father. Jyn went on to be raised by rebel leader Saw Gerrera. In “Rogue One,” we find Jyn as a wily young woman entangled in a quest to steal the very plans for the Death Star her father was being forced to build. Joining her is a diverse cast, which includes Imperial defector Bodhi Rook (Pakistani actor Riz Ahmed) and Captain Cassian Andor (Mexican actor Diego Luna). Overall, “Rogue One” is a well-crafted Star Wars story that artfully connects the original and prequel trilogies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tanjim Kazi</name></author><summary type="html">“I am one with the force—the force is with me” rings the mantra of warrior-monk Chirrut Îmwe in the latest film in the Star Wars universe: “Rogue One.” The force was indeed with “Rogue One” as it earned more than 800 million dollars its opening weekend. Chronologically, “Rogue” One” falls between Episodes 3 and 4, filling in the events leading up to the destruction of the first Death Star. The plot centers around Jyn Erso, the daughter of a scientist forced by the Empire to help build a planet-destroying weapon: the Death Star. As a child, Imperial Deathtroopers stormed Jyn’s planet, killing her mother, and kidnapping her father. Jyn went on to be raised by rebel leader Saw Gerrera. In “Rogue One,” we find Jyn as a wily young woman entangled in a quest to steal the very plans for the Death Star her father was being forced to build. Joining her is a diverse cast, which includes Imperial defector Bodhi Rook (Pakistani actor Riz Ahmed) and Captain Cassian Andor (Mexican actor Diego Luna). Overall, “Rogue One” is a well-crafted Star Wars story that artfully connects the original and prequel trilogies.</summary></entry></feed>